Finding Aid for Adolphus Mansfield Dudley papers, 1907-1945
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Adolphus Mansfield Dudley papers 1907-1945
Dudley, Adolphus Mansfield, 1877-
0.6 linear feet (in 2 boxes)
2009005 Aa 2
Electrical engineer; professional papers relating to his career at Westinghouse.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was donated by Dudley’s daughter-in-law Charlotte W. Wells (donor no. 10049 ) and came to the library in 2008.
No further additions to the papers are expected.
The collection is open to research.
Adolphus M. Dudley graduated from the University of Michigan earning his bachelor's degree in electrical engineering in 1902 and his master's degree in 1931. From 1904 to 1944, he was employed at the Westinghouse Electrical and Manufacturing Company.
The Dudley papers include correspondence, lectures, biographical information, and other records pertaining to his career at Westinghouse.
Subjects:
Dudley, Adolphus Mansfield, 1877-; Electric engineers.; Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company.
- Professional papers
  - Biographical Information (Box 1)
  - Career papers
    - 1907-1918 (Box 1)
      (AMD began working at Westinghouse in 1904)
    - 1919-1924 (Box 1)
    - 1925-1934 (Box 1)
    - 1935-1939 (Box 1)
    - 1940-1944 (Box 1)
  - 1925-1939 AMD as engineering educator (Box 1)
  - Patents, 1916-1945 (Box 1)
  - History of Westinghouse Co. (Box 1)
  - History of George Westinghouse (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - 1916-1939 (Box 1)
    - 1939-1945 (Box 1)
  - Articles and Books by AMD, 1908-1945 (Box 1)
  - Lectures
    - 1911-1924 (Box 1)
    - 1926-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1934-1942 (Box 2)
      (envelope of lecture notes 1934-1944 included)
  - University of Michigan: Application for graduate work, January 1931 (Box 2)
    (received Master of Science, Electrical Engineer, June 22, 1931)
  - University of Pittsburgh Master's Degree, 1933 (Box 2)
    (The title of his thesis was "The Graduate Student Training Course for Engineering of the Westinghouse Electric & Manufacturing Company"; this file includes related correspondence)
  - Membership in Engineering Honor Societies, Sigma Tau and Eta Kappa Nu (Box 2)
  - University of Michigan, Honorary Doctorate, 1939 (Box 2)
  - American Institute of Electrical Engineers, 1927-1931 (Box 2)
  - Retirement, honors and testimonials, 1944 (Box 2)
  - Ephemera (Box 2)